# Fabian Gunzinger

#### **②** fabiangunzinger.github.io **△** fa.gunzinger@gmail.com **in** fabiangunzinger **○** fabiangunzinger

I'm a behavioural and data scientist with 10+ years of research and 5+ years of project management experience in academia, central banking, and consulting. I use large datasets, insights from behavioural science, and methods from econometrics, causal inference, and machine learning to study human beahviour in the wild. The scientist in me loves doing this to further knowledge; the craftsman in me, to help build great products.

## **Education**

PhD in Behavioural Science, Warwick Business School	2019–2022 (expected)
MPhil in Economics, University of Oxford	2015–2017
MSc in Economics, University of Bern	2012–2014
BSc in Economics, University of Bern	2009–2012
Pre-university: commercial apprenticeship, military service, applied business studies	2001–2009

## Work experience

Data scientist, tracktheeconomy.ac.uk

2020-2021

- Designing and building interactive dashboard to track UK economic performance in real time at local level
- Working with private data providers to build fully automated pre-processing pipeline integrating all data assets such as individual-level bank-statement, mobile location data, and credit-scores (all of GB/TB-order size)
- Learning R and Shiny from scratch, and setting up and managing AWS resources (IAM, S3, EC2)

Research advisor, Behavioural Insights Team, London

2018-2019

- Designing, implementing, and analysing large-scale randomised controlled trials (A/B tests) and quasi-experimental evaluations across a range of policy areas in collaboration with our policy specialists and clients
- Training and mentoring colleagues in Stata programming and statistical methods

Research assistant, Department of Economics, University of Oxford

Autumn 2017

- Performing analysis of a large-scale randomised controlled trial in Kenya testing the effect of behavioural interventions
- Setting up code-sharing platform for the lab on GitHub and training colleagues to use it

Economist and staff to the Vice-Chairman, Swiss National Bank, Bern

2013-2015

Research scientist, Center for Health, Policy and Economics, University of Lucerne

Autumns 2014 and 2015

- Conducting data analysis for a project on the causal link between socioeconomic status and health behaviour using quasi-experimental methods
- Developing code for visualisations using ggplot2 that was used by the rest of the team

Intern, Credit Suisse Global Financial Market Research, Zurich,

Spring 2012

Research assistant, Chair of Applied Macroeconomics, ETH Zurich

2009-2013

#### Skills

Programming languages: Python, R, Stata, SQL

Tools: AWS, bash, Git, LATEX, Make

Languages: German (native), English (fluent), French (basic)

# **Teaching**

Big Data Analytics, Warwick Business School, Teaching assistant to Neil Stewart

Spring 2021

• Introduction to R (using R for Data Science) and machine learning (using An Introduction to Statistical Learning)

Private tutor, teaching econometrics and microeconomics to MBA, graduate, and undergraduate students

2015-2020

# **Publications**

Levelling Down and the COVID-19 Lockdowns: Uneven Regional Recovery in UK Consumer Spending

(with John Gathergood, Benedict Guttman-Kenney, Edika Quispe-Torreblanca and Neil Stewart) *CEPR Covid Economics*, 2021, vol. 67, pp. 24-52.

#### It's Politics, Stupid! Political Constraints Explain Government's Reactions to the Great Recession

(with Jan-Egbert Sturm, the paper is a version of my undergraduate thesis)

Kyklos, 2016, vol. 69(4), pp. 557-636. Reprinted in the International Monetary Fund book Fiscal Politics, 2017, pp. 177-213.

# Awards and honours

Warwick Business School PhD scholarship (full funding for 4 years)

Berrow Scholarship, Lincoln College, University of Oxford (full funding for MPhil degree)

Faculty Prize for graduating with highest honours (top 5 %) from MSc in Economics, University of Bern

Participant of the 11. Carroll Round (selective undergraduate conference), Georgetown University, Washington D.C., 2012